<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Gerald&#39;s Cabin • Posts by &#34;summary&#34; tag</title>
        <link>https://www.mechgerald.website</link>
        <description></description>
        <language>en,zh-cn,default</language>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 23:57:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 23:57:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <category>Travel</category>
        <category>Review</category>
        <category>Pixel Experience</category>
        <category>shell</category>
        <category>python</category>
        <category>Summary</category>
        <category>front end</category>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://www.mechgerald.website/2023/annualSummary22</guid>
            <title>The year 2022</title>
            <link>https://www.mechgerald.website/2023/annualSummary22</link>
            <category>Summary</category>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 23:57:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;apos;s not so much to summary, to be honest. But I felt like something needed to be done so as to make every day, every month matters in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;span id=&#34;more&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first few months were all messed up, to be fair. Failed at a major examination, wasted about a month preparing things that would never come true. However, looking back, the time was not totally wasted. It helped me realizing something about myself, something about what I&amp;apos;m capable of as well as what I&amp;apos;m not. It also helped to get back into some habits that I have lost during the college years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it&amp;apos;s not the kind of college life I was expecting. Even though passed all the test, graduated with no hard time, I was expecting it to be a lot more colorful. But who am I to blame except myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ways-to-know-a-city&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;ways-to-know-a-city&#34;&gt;Ways to know a city&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This, I&amp;apos;m not gonna lie, is my major gaining this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotta say that I had a whole different plan for the year. But I&amp;apos;m more than happy that things did not go as that. Turns out, I like it here, more than anywhere I&amp;apos;ve been. The six months I spent here really changed how I treat my life, probably in the best way I can see. One&amp;apos;s gotta go out and see things rather that just sitting in front of a desk with some books and a laptop. Life is about not just getting to know things, but also experiencing, appreciating and enjoying. With all the technologies upgrading, one can get a whole lot of information about a specific thing by just a click. But one can only get to fully know about it standing right there, breathing the same air over there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to know about a city, I gotta say, there&amp;apos;re four things at least one&amp;apos;s gonna do. One, paying some visit to the local museums, especially local cultural ones. Those museums are the fastest and most easy way to learn about the city. Two, visiting the parks. Parks are places where more detailed histories are stored. Every park, I mean, not the ones only for exercising, has a specific topic, the industrialization of the city, the natural environment, etc. Each park will provide some brand-new vision. However, I gotta say information parks can provide is not so much as museums. They are for relaxation, mostly. Three, spending some decent time in sports venues, libraries or book stores. It&amp;apos;s the easiest way to talk to strangers. You&amp;apos;ll need only one topic to start a real long talk, weather. Well, I guess it works in most circumstances. But in these places, one&amp;apos;s more likely to get to know people of the same interests. It&amp;apos;s very possible that a long-lasting relationship is formed during the communication, friendship, love, whatever it might be. And, last but not least, taking some random tours inside the city. There&amp;apos;re always places that one has never been to. My listing it last doesn&amp;apos;t mean that it should be done last. It&amp;apos;s the kind of thing that one can do every weekend. You got a car, drive wherever you want, a bike, ride. None? Pick a bus station with multiple transportation lines. Get on the next or whichever to arrive. Then get off at whichever station that attracts you, maybe for no reason. Make it random. Randomnesses enrich life, to a great extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#some-complaints&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;some-complaints&#34;&gt;Some Complaints&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Been waiting for a better year for three years. Finally a more &lt;em&gt;REGULAR&lt;/em&gt; year is coming into sight. I&amp;apos;m not gonna say a thing about whether it is right to put all the pressure on people against the pandemic. But being under so much pressure for the past three years has really made me clear about some particular things, which I might have to keep to myself for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;apos;re now looking at a much brighter sunrise, aren&amp;apos;t we? Even though we&amp;apos;ve paid the price, which was not so cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little off topic. LOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-expect-for-2023&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;what-to-expect-for-2023&#34;&gt;What to expect for 2023&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the working days, I came up with some idea about how to simplify my working routine so as to improve the efficiency. I might land on some of those after the Chinese NEW YEAR. Some posts might be on the way, HAHA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly skills, I think. One is never too old too learn, let alone being a fresh graduate. I now work mainly about CAE analysis. There&amp;apos;s a lot to learn about, ways to improve the simulating accuracy, ways to simplify modeling process, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A better location to live. There&amp;apos;s simply nothing to do in my neighborhood. One&amp;apos;s gonna need communication with other people to enrich life. Bars, playgrounds, libraries would be nice to be around. At least public transportation should be convenient to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowing down. People are thinking less nowadays. There&amp;apos;s just so much pressure everyday that people tend to go home and rest for the whole evening. With the development of internet technology, one get access to information in a much faster way. Side effects come with it. Taking in so much information in a short time leaves us no time to think. It&amp;apos;s time to put down the smart phones, and find a way to slow down the pace and enjoy life. Reading, meditating, learning some &lt;em&gt;soft&lt;/em&gt; instruments would be a way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: It&amp;apos;s Chinese new year&amp;apos;s night tonight! Happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
